#### SOFTWARE ARCHITECT · SECURITY EXPERT

73 Marshall St., Waterloo, ON, N2J 2T5

□ (+1) 647-238-9818 | **☑** pranavp2810@gmail.com | **營** pranavp.dev | **回** shadowp2810 | **□** vancepp

## Summary.

Canadian Open Work Permit (PGWP) until early 2023. Computer Science graduate, with the ability to effectively manage independent projects. Or work collaboratively within a team environment by actively listening, motivating, and maintaining effective communication across all stakeholders. Applying best practices to achieve operational effectiveness, while keeping to the timeline of the projects at hand to meet organizational goals and mission. Dedicated to expanding my technical expertise and management ability. I am actively pursuing a role in information security and cloud architecture, technology and business analysis, UI/UX design, people centric roles and software development.

### **Certifications**

CompTIA Security+ (Feb 2021-2024)

IN PROGRESS: AWS Solutions Architect Associate (exp. April 20th); AWS Security Speciality (exp. April 27th)

### Skills\_

AWS Services (EC2. ECS. S3. SNS. SQS. VPC. Route53. CloudFront. IAM. AutoScaling. DynamoDB. CloudFormation. CloudWatch. AWS WAF. GuardDuty. Shield. RDS.) Docker. React-Native. GraphQL. TypeScript. Kali-Linux. NodeJS. MERN Stack. InVision. Java. UI/UX design. HTML5 / CSS. Python. Sketch. Objective-C. AWS Amplify. JavaScript. MongoDB. SQL. Angular. C++. Power BI. Figma. Network security. Risk management. Threat intelligence. Data and host security. Identity management. Cryptography and PKI.

## **Projects**

### **Personal Projects**

REACT NATIVE TWITTER | WHATSAPP | TINDER CLONE

Oct. 2020 - Jan. 2020

- Front-End: React Native Expo App for Android and iOS.
- Back-End: AWS Amplify Auth, S3 Storage, and GraphQL API.

#### **University Projects**

Sep. 2015 - Dec. 2019

- Developed a traffic simulator program in Java. Maple to visualize the data to show that even in a no bottleneck scenario, traffic jams can occur.
- Used python to code robot behavior in ROS kinetic.
- Developed a scheduler program with a group using Java.
- Implementation of Search Algorithms and Reinforcement learning using JavaScript.
- Designed a new UI and UX for university's mobile app addressing all previous faults.
- Developed a university website with a group using HTML, CSS and JavaScript. My primary responsibility was the Google Maps API component for students to navigate to and between campuses.
- Worked on team project of single-player 2D platform web game requiring asset creation, game engine and level editor.

# Work Experience\_

### **P28INKS Apparel Store**

Waterloo, ON, Canada

CREATOR

Oct. 2020 - Dec. 2020

- · Set up and management of online Shopify store, and print on demand service for automated order and shipping.
- Design of apparel and Search Engine Optimization (SEO).

### **Memorial University of Newfoundland**

St. John's, NL, Canada

COMPUTER SCIENCE RESEARCH ASSISTANT

Jan. 2018 - May. 2018

• Researched and reported on Blockchain, Distributed Systems, IOT, and Cloud Technology.

### **Memorial University of Newfoundland**

St. John's, NL, Canada

SOCIOLINGUISTIC RESEARCH ASSISTANT

April. 2016 - Aug. 2016

• Detailed transcription of interviews with focus on phonetic shifting.

## **Education**

### **MUN(Memorial University of Newfoundland)**

St. John's, NL, Canada

B.Sc. IN COMPUTER SCIENCE

Sep. 2015 - Feb. 2020